[
    {
        "front": "Dirac Notation: What is the difference between a **bra** and a **ket** ?",
        "back": "Both represent a quantum state, however they are defined in dual space. A ket $|\\Psi\\rangle$ is a **vector**, while a bra $\\langle\\Psi|$ is a **map**."
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the similarity and difference between uncertainty in the uncertainty principle, and classical uncertainty?",
        "back": "Discuss the difference between the classical and quantum uncertainty."
    },
    {
        "front": "Discuss the impact and relevance of the **no-cloning** theorem.",
        "back": "Discuss."
    },
    {
        "front": "How is an entangled state different from a generic superposition?",
        "back": "The answer lies in the structure of the Hilbert space. Both are superpositions, however entangled states manifest when we combine two or more quantum systems. Discuss."
    },
    {
        "front": "How important is quantum tunneling? Would we have quantum gates if tunneling didn't exist?",
        "back": "Discuss."
    },
    {
        "front": "Why do we need normalized vectors for a quantum state. Can't we work with a vectors of arbitrary magnitude?",
        "back": "The state $|s\\rangle = c_1|1\\rangle + c_2|2\\rangle + ... c_n|n\\rangle$ has probability $|c_i|^2$ which should sum up to 1."
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the mathematical implication of the measurement of the quantum state, what happens to the vector when measured in a basis?",
        "back": "Discuss"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the connection between the operators and observables?",
        "back": "Discuss what does a quantum measurement do, and how it is mathematically interpreted."  
    },
    {
        "front": "How do you combine the Hilbert space created by multiple qubits? How do the vectors change and how do the operators change?",
        "back": "Discuss how does the bigger system looks like, and how it changes the scale of the problem."
    },
    {
        "front": "When we *add* qubits the Hilbert space becomes bigger, i.e., dimension grows as $2^n$. What are *storage* implications of this?",
        "back": "A single qubit has as many states as points on unit sphere. Say, we discretized the points to 100, then the number of possible states scales as $100^n=10^{2n}$. Compare this to classical scaling of storage."
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the primary distinction between pure and mixed states? Why do we need mixed states?",
        "back": "A pure state is an ideal quantum object represented by a vector/ket. A mixed state is a classical ensemble of quantum states and is expressed through a density operator. We need mixed states when classical uncertainty is added to the problem."
    }
]
